Now that we've walked through all of the elements of VQE, let's
VQEのすべての要素を説明したところで、
summarize what we've learned and see how a quantum computer executes it.
学んだことをまとめ、量子コンピューターがどのように実行するかを見てみましょう。
We start off with our cleverly chosen reference state, parameterized circuit,
まず、巧みに選んだ参照状態、パラメーター化されたcircuit、
initial choice of parameters and a Hamiltonian.
パラメーターの初期値、そしてハミルトニアンから始めます。
We pass these to our quantum computer.
これらを量子コンピューターに渡します。
Before the Hamiltonian can be executed on the ansatz state,
ハミルトニアンをansatz状態で実行する前に、
we need to do classical pre-processing of the circuit
circuitの古典的な前処理を行う必要があります。
to make it readable by quantum hardware in a process called transpilation.
これはトランスパイルと呼ばれる工程で、量子ハードウェアが読み取れる形に変換します。
It's also important to take the most advantage
また、最良の結果を得るために
of the architecture of qubits in the real hardware to get the best results.
実際のハードウェア上のqubitアーキテクチャを最大限に活用することも重要です。
These processes are often taken care of automatically so that we don't
これらの処理は多くの場合、自動的に行われるため、私たちが
explicitly have to know qubit connectivity,
qubitの接続性や
gate fidelities and so on.
gateの忠実度などを明示的に意識する必要はありません。
Now the task is to measure the resulting state
次のタスクは、結果の状態を測定し、
and estimate the expectation value, which will be further
期待値を推定することです。これはさらに
optimized by a classical optimizer.
古典的なオプティマイザーによって最適化されます。
This measurement is performed by rotating measurement basis
この測定は、測定基底を回転させることで行われます。
and then combining the measurement results to obtain the expectation value.
そして測定結果を組み合わせて期待値を求めます。
This parameterized result is then fed
このパラメーター化された結果は、
into the classical optimizer, which finds new parameters for the state.
古典的なオプティマイザーに渡され、状態の新しいパラメーターが求められます。
Then the process is repeated.
そして、このプロセスが繰り返されます。
A classical pre-processing creates a new parameterized circuit
古典的な前処理によって新しいパラメーター化されたcircuitが生成され、
and we apply the same Hamiltonian as before.
先ほどと同じハミルトニアンを適用します。
Note that in the whole VQE process we only change the states
VQEプロセス全体を通して変えるのは状態だけであり、
through the parameters which get closer and closer to the ground state.
パラメーターを通じて基底状態へと少しずつ近づいていきます。
We repeat this until we're satisfied with the result.
満足のいく結果が得られるまで、これを繰り返します。
And that's it.
以上です。
My name is Victoria Lipinska and this was a variational quantum eigensolver course.
私はVictoria Lipinskaです。変分量子固有値ソルバーのコースでした。